# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hey guys this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In today's video I am gonna share with you a homely dish
# 干炸猪肉丸
Deep-fried pork meatballs
# 首先我们准备五花肉一大块约500克
First, prepare a lump of pork belly (about 500g)
# 将肉皮取下之后先切成薄片
remove the skin and cut it into thin slices
# 然后再剁成肉泥备用
chop the pork to a pasty consistency
# 同学们五花肉最好选择肥瘦1:1
It is better to choose pork belly half fat and half lean
# 这样炸出来的丸子口感均衡不油腻
so that the meatballs will not taste too greasy
# 肉泥剁好之后放入盆中下一步开始腌制
Put the meat mash into a pot for seasoning
# 盆中加入适量的食用盐（约3克）
Add some salt to taste (about 3g)
# 加入适量的料酒（约5克）
some Chinese cooking wine to taste (about 5g)
# 然后搅拌均匀顺着一个方向摔打上劲
Mix thoroughly, and toss the mixture in one direction
# 这一步的目的是让肉泥吸收调料摔打出肉胶
Until the seasoning ingredients permeate into the meat, and it becomes elastic
# 将肉泥摔打至出胶黏手即可
Knead and toss the meat mash until sticky and elastic
# 然后准备适量的姜葱切成细丝
Prepare some ginger and scallions and cut into julienne strips
# 姜葱丝切好之后放入碗中
Put the shreds into a bowl
# 加入适量的清水用力抓1分钟抓出姜葱水
Add some water, squeeze the shreds until the flavour comes out into the water
# 这一步没有直接把姜葱加入到肉泥中
We do not mix the ginger and scallions with the meat
# 是因为姜葱下锅之后容易炸糊
to avoid overcooking them during deep-frying
# 盆中加入胡椒粉一勺（约1.5克）
Add a spoonful of pepper (about 1.5g)
# 然后把处理好的姜葱水倒入盆中
Pour the ginger-scallion-flavoured water into the pot
# 再将肉泥继续搅拌至完全吸收水份为止
Mix until the water is completely absorbed
# 同学们切记不可将所有的调料一起放入搅拌
Remember not to put and mix all the ingredients at once
# 每一道程序都是最科学的安排
We have careful arrangements for each step
# 缺少层次感的菜品是没有灵魂的
A dish is souless if it does not have well-rounded taste
# 搅拌上劲之后加入鸡蛋1个
Crack an egg into the bowl after tossing
# 再加入适量的玉米淀粉搅打上劲
And add a proper amount of corn starch, mix, knead, and toss until elastic
# 玉米淀粉勾芡的效果略差
Corn starch is more suitable for deep-frying meatballs
# 但相比于土豆淀粉来说更适合炸肉丸
Although it is not as effective as potato starch in thickening the sauce
# 搅拌上劲之后下一步开始制作
Let's begin cooking when it's all ready
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入宽油
Pour in Kuan You (lit: broad oil, a huge amount of oil)
# 然后将油温烧至6成热（约180度）
Heat the oil up to about 180 °C
# 油温6成热之后将准备好的肉泥挤成丸子依次下入锅中
Shape the meatballs from the mash and put them into the wok one by one
# 同学们切记炸丸子的油温不能低于180度
Remember to keep the temperature above 180°C
# 否则下锅容易自动散开或者多个丸子黏在一起
Otherwise the meatball might lose its shape, or various meatballs may stick together
# 丸子下锅之后将其炸至熟透备用
Deep-fry the meatballs until fully cooked
# 肉丸熟透之后捞出转大火将油温升至190度
Take out the meatballs and heat the oil up to 190 °C
# 然后再次将丸子下锅复炸30秒
Put in the meatballs, fry again for 30 seconds
# 这一步的目的是将肉丸表面收紧炸脆
In order to tighten the shape and give them a crispy crust
# 秒钟之后将肉丸捞出即可
After 30 seconds, take out the meatballs and the dish is ready
# 一道外酥里嫩的炸肉丸就制作完成
Crispy deep-fried meatballs with tender inner texture are now finished
# 下面开始技术总结
Here are some tips
# 第一，此菜可以作为成菜上桌，也可以作为半成品
These meatballs are ready to be served as a fully-finished dish, but can also work as half-done ingredients
# 第二，可以加入辅料将其红烧或者煮汤
That's why they can be further used for cooking soup or red-braising, together with some side ingredients
# 第二，复炸的时候可以多复炸几次以确保外酥里嫩
You can fry again for a few more times, to make sure the meatballs have a crispy and tender texture
# 炸肉丸的技术总结完毕
That's all for the tips